Guide to the McCormick family papers, 1900-1941.
McCormick family papers, 1900-1941.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
McCormick family papers, 1900-1941.
1312
8.6 cubic ft.
Prime prints, tear sheets, sketches, lecture slides, linoleum blocks, glass plate negatives, photonegatives, correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Consists mostly of graphic arts materials of Howard McCormick and correspondence of family and friends.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Consists mostly of graphic arts materials of Howard McCormick, representing his work as a wood engraver, cover designer, illustrator, and muralist, and includes prime prints, tear sheets, sketches, lecture slides, linoleum blocks, glass plate negatives of Navajo, Hopi, and Apache Indian dances, photonegatives of a trip to Mexico, a wood engraving print of Abraham Lincoln's head, magazine articles written by McCormick, exhibition catalogs, and similar materials. Also includes letters to Howard McCormick from his brother Frederick, a Reuter's correspondent in the Far East, in which he describes living conditions, customs, and superstitions among the Chinese, recounts his experiences reporting the Russo-Japanese War, and gives his impressions of the Russians; and business and personal correspondence from relatives and family friends. Correspondents include Carl Akeley, Josephine Newell, and Grace McCormick Wilson.
Includes a woodblock print by Howard McCormick of Borglum's bust of Lincoln.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McCormick family.; Akeley, Carl.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865.; McCormick, Frederick, b. 1870.; McCormick, Howard.; Newell, Josephine.; Wilson, Grace McCormick.
Subjects:
Graphic arts.; Navajo Indians.; Hopi dance.; Apache Indians.; Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905.; Russians.; Artists.
Places:
China.
Form and Genre Terms:
Glass plate negatives.; Photonegatives.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1900-1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1907-1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1933-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- McCormick Family Miscellany (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Miscellany including tear sheets, pamphlets, certificates concerning Howard McCormick's art work (Box 1, Folder 8-13)
- Newpaper Clippings (Box 1, Folder 14-20)
- Gutzon Borglum's Head of Lincoln: engraving on wood block by Howard McCormick and electrotype for magazine reproduction (see box 10) (Box 2)
- Photographs and Negatives: Mexico (Box 3)
- Lantern Slides: Old Mexico; Wood Engraving Lecture (Box 4)
- Lantern Slides: Wood Engraving Lecture (Box 5)
- Lantern Slides: Southwestern Indians - Hopi and Navajo (Box 6)
- Lantern Slides: Southwestern Indians (Box 7)
- Photographs: Southwestern Indians (Box 8)
- Glass Plates, Photogrpahs, Negatives: Europe (Italy and France); Gessos; Murals; Portrait of Howard McCormick; McCormick and Friends (Box 9)
- Sketches, Paintings, Engravings, etc. (Lincoln paint and proof) (Box 10-11)
- Tear Sheets and Other Examples of McCormick's Work (Box 12)
- Linoleum Printing Blocks (Box 13)
- Engraving Tools and Wooden Box (Box 14)
- Wood Engraving Blocks (Box 15-16)
- L'Marold Album - Engravings by McCormick (Box 17)
- Engravings, Sketches, Paintings, etc. (Folder 1-2)